A Guide to the Papers of Edgar Allan Poe, 1826-1955
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of Edgar Allan Poe
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Multiple numbers
This collection consists of ca. 270 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
#38-135: Purchase, March 17, 1922 #38-623: Gift, 1900. #59: Gift, July 30, 1938 #957-b: Gift, 1922 #1018-k: Deposit, November 2, 1988 #1083: Transferred to RG-23/34/1.411. Deposit, March 21, 1941 #2253: Gift, March 29, 1988 #3565-a: Gift, March 26, 1973 #3857: Gift, January 16, 1952 #3857-a: Deposit, April 23, 1960. Gift July 1, 1991 #3857-b: Gift, April 30, 1960. #3857-c: Purchase, December 3, 1965. #3857-d: Deposit, February 4, 1966. Gift July 1, 1991 #3857-e: Purchase, June 3, 1965. #4610: January 26, 1954 #4647: Deposit, February 22, 1954 #5153-a: Withdrawn, December 21, 1998 #6012-b: Gift, May 15, 1968 #6577: Gift, August 8, 1961 #7838-a: Archival Transfer, November 29, 1973 #8795: Purchase, February 2, 1968 #8824-p: Gift, January 17, 1973 #9477: Gift, May 7, 1970 #10116-e: Gift, April 20, 1978 #10213-b: Purchase, 1977/1978 #10251: Purchase, October 19, 1977 #10686: No information #14478: Purchase, December 16, 2008.
Biographical/Historical Information
Born January 19, 1809, in Boston, Mass.; died from complications related to a brain lesion, October 7, 1849, in Baltimore, Md.; buried in Westminster Presbyterian Churchyard, Baltimore; son of David, Jr. (a lawyer-turned actor; died 1811) and Elizabeth (an English actress; maiden name, Arnold; died 1811) Poe; unofficially adopted, 1811, by John (a tobacco merchant) and Frances Allan; married Virginia Clemm (a cousin), May 16, 1836 (died, 1847). Education: Attended Manor House School, Stoke Newington, England, 1815-20, University of Virginia, 1826, and United States Military Academy at West Point, 1830-31.
Novelist, critic, short story writer, and poet. Southern Literary Messenger, Richmond, Va., staff member, 1835-36, assistant editor, 1836-37; Burlington Gentleman's Magazine, Philadelphia, PA, co-editor, 1839- 40; Graham's Lady's and Gentleman's Magazine, literary editor, 1841-42; Evening Mirror, New York City, staff member, 1845; Broadway Journal, editor and owner, 1845-46. Military service: Enlisted in the United States Army under name Edgar A. Perry, 1827; became regimental sergeant-major, 1829; discharged, 1829.
First prize (fiction), Baltimore Saturday Visiter [sic], 1833, for "MS. Found in a Bottle"; first prize (fiction), Philadelphia Dollar Newspaper, 1843, for "The Gold Bug."
Poe's stature as a major figure in world literature is primarily based on his ingenious and profound short stories, poems, and critical theories, which established a highly influential rationale for the short form in both poetry and fiction. Regarded in literary histories and handbooks as the architect of the modern short story, Poe was also the principal forerunner of the "art for art's sake" movement in nineteenth- century European literature. Whereas earlier critics predominantly concerned themselves with moral or ideological generalities, Poe focused his criticism on the specifics of style and construction that contributed to a work's effectiveness or failure. In his own work, he demonstrated a brilliant command of language and technique as well as an inspired and original imagination. Poe's poetry and short stories greatly influenced the French Symbolists of the late nineteenth century, who in turn altered the direction of modern literature. It is this philosophical and artistic transaction that accounts for much of Poe's importance in literary history.
Poe's father and mother were professional actors who at the time of his birth were members of a repertory company in Boston. Before Poe was three years old both of his parents died, and he was raised in the home of John Allan, a prosperous exporter from Richmond, Virginia, who never legally adopted his foster son. As a boy, Poe attended the best schools available, and was admitted to the University of Virginia at Charlottesville in 1825. While there he distinguished himself academically but was forced to leave after less than a year because of bad debts and inadequate financial support from Allan. Poe's relationship with Allan disintegrated upon his return to Richmond in 1827, and soon after Poe left for Boston, where he enlisted in the army and also published his first poetry collection, Tamerlane, and Other Poems. The volume went unnoticed by readers and reviewers, and a second collection, Al Aaraaf, Tamerlane, and Minor Poems, received only slightly more attention when it appeared in 1829. That same year Poe was honorably discharged from the army, having attained the rank of regimental sergeant major, and was then admitted to the United States Military Academy at West Point. However, because Allan would neither provide his foster son with sufficient funds to maintain himself as a cadet nor give the consent necessary to resign from the Academy, Poe gained a dismissal by ignoring his duties and violating regulations. He subsequently went to New York City, where Poems, his third collection of verse, was published in 1831, and then to Baltimore, where he lived at the home of his aunt, Mrs. Maria Clemm.
Over the next few years Poe's first short stories appeared in the Philadelphia Saturday Courier and his "MS. Found in a Bottle" won a cash prize for best story in the Baltimore Saturday Visitor. Nevertheless, Poe was still not earning enough to live independently, nor did Allan's death in 1834 provide him with a legacy. The following year, however, his financial problems were temporarily alleviated when he accepted an editorship at The Southern Literary Messenger in Richmond, bringing with him his aunt and his twelve-year-old cousin Virginia, whom he married in 1836. The Southern Literary Messenger was the first of several journals Poe would direct over the next ten years and through which he rose to prominence as a leading man of letters in America. Poe made himself known not only as a superlative author of poetry and fiction, but also as a literary critic whose level of imagination and insight had hitherto been unapproached in American literature.
While Poe's writings gained attention in the late 1830s and early 1840s, the profits from his work remained meager, and he supported himself by editing Burton's Gentleman's Magazine and Graham's Magazine in Philadelphia and the Broadway Journal in New York City. After his wife's death from tuberculosis in 1847, Poe became involved in a number of romantic affairs. It was while he prepared for his second marriage that Poe, for reasons unknown, arrived in Baltimore in late September of 1849. On October 3, he was discovered in a state of semi-consciousness; he died four days later without regaining the necessary lucidity to explain what had happened during the last days of his life.
Scope and Content
The Papers of Edgar Allen Poe consist of literary manuscripts, correspondence, miscellaneous documents, and numerous prints and engravings. Correspondence includes family and business matters, some dealing with publication matters. There are also letters from Maria Clemm, mother of Virginia Clemm, discussing Edgar Allen Poe and Virginia Clemm.
Correspondents include: Mary A. Benjamin, Maria Clemm, George W. Eveleth, James A. Harrison, John Pendleton Kennedy, June E. Locke, Charles G. Percival, Edgar Allen Poe, Annie L. Richmond, J. H. Whitty, Laura Stedman, and Thomas W. White.
Included in literary manuscripts is an article by Edgar Allen Poe, entitled "The Rationale of Verse," in which he explicates his own poem, "Al Aaraaf." Also are Edgar Allen Poe's corrections of a play by Estella Lewis and hand-written copies of her poems. Two poems by William Henry Poe, the brother of Edgar Allen Poe, are also included, which are handwritten by the editor of Minerva.
Miscellaneous Documents, or Series III, contains two promissory notes, receipts, and Jefferson Society Minutes in the hand of Edgar Allen Poe.
The photographs, prints and illustrative material includes copies the major daguerreotypes of Edgar Allen Poe ("McKee," "Painter," "Pratt," "Stella," "Ultima Thule," "West Point," and "Whitehurst") as well as images of persons and places associated with his work.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged in four series: Series I: Literary Manuscripts. Series II: Correspondence. Series III: Miscellaneous Documents. Series IV: Photographs, Prints and Illustrative Material.
Contents List
- Series I: Literary Manuscripts
  - The Rationale of Verse from The Southern Literary Messenger, page 23 [ca. 1848], AMs, 1 p. on 1 l. (Box-folder 1:1)
    Page from Literary Criticism on Richard H. Horne's Chaucer Modernized, mentioning his own Al Aaraaf. #3857
  - Edgar Allan Poe's Autograph Corrections of Estella Lewis' "The Prisoner of Perote." [ca. late 1848], AMs, 4 pp. on 3 l. (Box-folder 1:2)
    "These corrections and the note in pencil on the last page are Poe's in his hand writing - Estella." Silked. #38-135
  - Isabella n.d., AMs, 1 p. on 1 l. (Box-folder 1:3)
    Copy of a stanza of Mrs. S. A. Lewis' poem by Edgar Allan Poe. #3857
  - To Minna and To ---- by William Henry Poe n.d., AMs, 4 pp. on 1 l. (Box-folder 1:4)
    Written in the hand of the Editor of Minerva, including two poems by William Henry Poe, brother of Edgar Allan Poe, with a biographical note regarding the life of William Henry Poe. #8795
- Series II: Correspondence
  - Mary A Benjamin to Mr. C. Waller Barrett 1955 November 22, TLS, 1 p. on 1 l. (Box-folder 1:5)
    Regarding authenticity of Poe painting. See James A. Harrison correspondence and Laura Stedman correspondence. #3857-d
  - Maria Clemm to [John Neal] 1850 April 11, ALS, 1 p. on 1 l. (Box-folder 1:6)
    With photocopy. #4610
  - Maria Clemm to "Dear Louise," [18]50 September 16, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l. (Box-folder 1:7)
    With photocopy. #3857
  - M[aria] Clemm to "Darling Loui[se]" 1851 January 3, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l. (Box-folder 1:8)
    Parke-Bernet folder with penciled note '937.' With photocopy. #3857
  - "Muddie" [Maria Clemm] to "My dear friend" [Gabriel Harrison?] [18]65 October 6, ALS, 1 p. on 1 l. (Box-folder 1:9)
  - George W. Eveleth to Edgar Allan Poe 1849 July 3, ALS, 4 pp. on 1 l. (Box-folder 1:10)
    With photocopy. #3857-c
  - James A. Harrison to Henry S. [Borneman] 1900 September 30, ALS, 4 pp. on 2 l., with envelope. (Box-folder 1:11)
    Regarding Edgar Allan Poe painting; see Mary A. Benjamin correspondence, folder 3. #3857-d
  - James A. Harrison to Henry S. Borneman 1901 June 21, APCS, 1 p. on 1 l. (Box-folder 1:12)
  - John Pendleton Kennedy to Edgar Allan Poe 1836 April 26, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l., with address leaf. (Box-folder 1:13)
    #3857
  - June [E.] Locke to Mr. [Rufus W.] Griswald [1850?] October 12, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l. (Box-folder 1:14)
    #3857-d
  - Charles G. Percival to Edgar Allen Poe 1845 December 19, ALS, 1 p. on 1 l., with address leaf and postmark. (Box-folder 1:15)
    Includes Edgar Allan Poe's hand-written notation on top left of correspondence and text of Edgar Allan Poe's reply. Extreme mold-damage. #8795
  - Edgar Allan Poe to Beverly Tucker 1835 December 1, 2 pp. on 1 l., with address leaf, postmark, and partial wax seal. (Box-folder 1:16)
    #6012-b
  - Edgar Allan Poe to John C. McCabe 1836 March 3, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l. (Box-folder 1:17)
    #4647
  - Edgar Allan Poe to Washington Irving 1841 June 21, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l., with address leaf and postmark, docketed. (Box-folder 1:18)
    Includes transcription, photograph copy, and description. Barrow Process. #3857
  - Edgar Allan Poe to F. W. Thomas 1841 September 1, ALS, 1 p. on 1 l., with address leaf and postmark, docketed. (Box-folder 1:19)
  - Edgar Allan Poe to Dr. Thomas H. Chives 1842 July 6, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l., with address leaf and postmark. (Box-folder 1:20)
    Mounted. #3857-a
  - Edgar Allan Poe to J. and H.G. Langley [1842 July 18], ALS, 1 p. on 1 l., with address and postmark on verso. (Box-folder 1:20a)
    Poe, [Philadelphia] writes to the New York publishers enclosing an article for the Democratic Review. He is "desperately pushed for money" and would like the usual sum in payment before the 21st. He apologizes for his drunken behavior when in New York and blames the juleps forced on him by [William Ross] Wallace. He discusses his review of Rufus Dawes' poetry which was later published in Graham's magazine. #14478
  - Edgar Allan Poe to L. J. Cist 1844 June 3, ALS, 1 p. on 1 l., with address leaf and postmark, docketed. (Box-folder 1:21)
    #4610
  - Edgar Allan Poe to "My Dear Sir" [unidentified] [1846?] April 28, ALS, 1 p. on 1 l. (Box-folder 1:22)
    Negative Photostat. #3857-d
  - Edgar Allan Poe to N. P. Willis 1846 December 7, ALS facsimile, 1 p. on 1 l. with address leaf. (Box-folder 1:23)
    "Counterfeit" written in pencil in top right corner. #3857-d
  - Edgar Allan Poe to [Robert T. Conrad] 1847 August 10, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l. (Box-folder 1:24)
    Presented to the Poe Alcove by Prof. James A. Harrison, 1900. #38-623
  - Eddy [Edgar Allan Poe] to Annie [Richmond] 1848 November 16, ALS copy, 4 pp. on 1 l. (Box-folder 1:25)
    Includes note by John Ingram in pen on top of copy: "This must be burnt. JHI." Includes transcription and negative photostat. #38-135
  - Edgar Allan Poe to Edward Valentine 18[48] November 20, ALS, 2 p. on 1 l., with address leaf. (Box-folder 1:26)
    Regarding "Stylus." #5153-a
  - Edgar [Allan Poe] to Annie [Richmond] [1849] February 19, ALS copy, 5 pp. on 2 l. (Box-folder 1:27)
    Includes note by Mrs. Richmond to Mr. Ingram. #38-135
  - Edgar Allan Poe to [unidentified] n.d., ALS fragment with attached signature, 1 p. on 1 l. (Box-folder 1:28)
    Ostrom, item 307-a in supplement. Ostrom gives this a conjectural date of [March 1 (?), 1849] and conjectures that the addressee is Annie L. Richmond [?]. Mounted. #3857-c
  - Edgar Allan Poe to Mary Osborne n.d., ANS, 1 p. on 1 l. (Box-folder 1:29)
    Photograph. #3857
  - Annie L. Richmond to Mr. Gill 1882 February 26, ALS, 3 pp. on 1 l. (Box-folder 1:30)
    Regarding Edgar Allan Poe biography. #8795
  - J. H. Whitty to William F. Gill 1909 June 24, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l. (Box-folder 1:31)
  - J. H. Whitty to William F. Gill 1909 July 26, ALS, 4 pp. on 1 l. (Box-folder 1:32)
  - Laura Stedman to Henry S. Borneman 1900 October 8, ALS, 3 pp. on 1 l., with envelope. (Box-folder 1:33)
  - Thomas W. White to "Dear Sir" [unidentified] 1839 December 10, ALS, 1 p. on 1 l. (Box-folder 1:34)
    Notated in pencil at bottom of letter: "Editor of Southern Lit. Mess.; Poe's employer, 1835-1836." #3857-d
- Series III: Miscellaneous Documents
  - Promissory Note by Edgar Allan Poe to [Daniel S.] Mosby and Company 1826 December 14, DS, 1 p. on 1 l. (Box-folder 1:35)
    Included Photographic reproductions and photostat copies. #38-623
  - Edgar Allan Poe note and signature of the Jefferson Society Minutes while secretary for the Jefferson Society at the University of Virginia 1826, ANS, 1 p. on 1 l. (Box-folder 1:36)
    mounted in large framed item, #1018-k
  - Receipt of subscription payment to the Southern Literary Messenger by Mr. N. Biddle [1841], DS, 1 p. on 1 l. (Box-folder 1:37)
  - Promissory Note by Edgar Allan Poe to Swain, Abell & Simmons 1842 May 25, ADS, 1 p. on 1 l. (Box-folder 1:38)
  - Southern Literary Messenger subscription receipt signed by Edgar Allan Poe 1845 April 30, ADS facsimile, 1 p. on 1 l. (Box-folder 1:39)
  - A Catalogue of Valuable Standard Works [1846], 2 items. (Box-folder 1:40)
    Cover and page 53. Photostats. #3857-d
  - Page of a manuscript from Edgar Allan Poe's Marginalia n.d., 1 item. (Box-folder 1:41)
    Photograph. #3857-d
  - The Murders in the Rue Morgue n.d., 1 item. (Box-folder 1:42)
    First page of printed edition. Photograph. #3857-d
  - The Murder of Mary Rogers n.d., 1 item. (Box-folder 1:43)
    Photograph of newspaper article. #3857
  - "Edgar Allan Poe" by Charles W. Hubner 1909, AMsS, 1 p. on 1 l. (Box-folder 1:44)
    Poem read at the University of Virginia Poe Centennial Celebration, 1909. Housed in red slipcase. "Presented to the University of Virginia on the occasion of the Dedication of the Clifton Waller Barrett Library of American Literature April 30, 1960." #3857-b
- Series IV: Photographs, Prints and Illustrative Material
  - Daguerreotypes
    - McKee Daguerreotype
      - Derivative images n.d., 4 items (Box-folder 2:1)
        R. G. Tietze engraving.
        #38-135
    - Painter Daguerreotype
      - Painter daguerreotype n.d., 7 photographic copies and 6 photocopies. (Box-folder 2:2)
        Also includes photocopy of an article from the Baltimore Sun Times Magazine, Sep. 19, 1982, re the Painter daguerreotype. #38-135
    - Pratt Daguerreotype
      - Pratt daguerreotype n.d., 3 photographic copies. (Box-folder 2:3)
        Thompson variant of this is known (1981) to be at Columbia University.
      - Derivative images n.d., 13 prints and engravings. (Box-folder 2:4)
        Includes portrait by Oscar Halling; engraving by Robert Lee Traylor; engraving by Frederick T. Stuart. #38-135, #38-138, #6577, #8824-p
    - Stella Daguerreotype
      - Stella daguerreotype n.d., 7 photographic copies; 1 photocopy. (Box-folder 2:5)
      - Derivative images n.d., 7 prints and engravings. (Box-folder 2:6)
        Engraving by Frederick Warne & Company. #38-135
    - Ultima Thule Daguerreotype
      - Ultima Thule daguerreotype n.d., 6 photographic copies. (Box-folder 2:7)
        Includes 1 carte de visite by Manchester Bros., Westminster Street, Providence, R.I. #7055, #7838-a
      - Derivative images n.d., 14 prints and engravings. (Box-folder 2:8)
        Includes Timothy Cole engraving, A. G. Learned engraving, and Eugene Perry engraving. Also includes 1 carte de visite of Brady pose, published by E. & H.T. Anthony & Co., 591 Broadway, New York. #38-135, #7838-a
    - West Point Daguerreotype
      - West Point daguerreotype n.d., 2 photographic copies. (Box-folder 2:9)
        #7838-a
    - Whitehurst Daguerreotype
      - Whitehurst daguerreotype [1849], 3 photographic copies and 1 photocopy. (Box-folder 2:10)
      - Derivative images [1874], 1 carte de visite photograph, M.P. Simons, Philadelphia. (Box-folder 2:11)
    - Whitman Daguerreotype
      - Whitman daguerreotype n.d., 1 carte de visite photograph by Coleman & Remington, 25 Westminster St., Prov., R.I. 1 print from unidentified source. (Box-folder 2:12)
  - Portraits
    - Robert Evans Breck portrait of Edgar Allan Poe [ca. 1974], 1 item. Photograph. (Box-folder 2:13)
      UVa Art index 635. #10116-e
    - J. Carlin portrait of Edgar Allan Poe n.d., 1 item. Photograph. (Box-folder 2:14)
      Includes related correspondence and negative photostat.
    - Francis Darley portrait of Edgar Allan Poe n.d., 1 item. Photostat. (Box-folder 2:15)
    - Articles regarding "Eddy" portrait of Edgar Allan Poe 1982, 3 items. Photocopies. (Box-folder 2:16)
    - Dwight Franklin portrait of Edgar Allan Poe on Sullivan's Island [1829 January], 1 item. Photograph. (Box-folder 2:17)
      Received from Charleston, S. C. Museum, July 1923.
    - Oscar Halling portrait of Edgar Allan Poe; Thompson derivative [ca. 1868], 4 items. (Box-folder 2:18)
      See Barrett-Poe oversize box for larger print. #38-135
    - George P. A. Healy portrait of Edgar Allan Poe n.d., 1 item. Framed. (Box-folder 2:19)
      Includes 2 black and white 8x10 photographic reproductions. #10686.
    - Charles Hine portrait of Edgar Allan Poe n.d., 1 item. Print. (Box-folder 2:20)
      See Barrett-Poe oversize for larger print. Mounted. #38-135.
    - Henry Inman portrait of Edgar Allan Poe n.d., 1 item, Photograph. (Box-folder 2:21)
      #6577
    - Henry Inman portrait of [Edgar Allan Poe?] n.d., 1 item. Photograph. (Box-folder 2:22)
    - H. G. K. portrait of Edgar Allan Poe n.d., 1 item. Photograph. (Box-folder 2:23)
      Original owned by Walter Pasko.
    - Charles Keelmann portrait of Edgar Allan Poe 1837, 1 item. Photograph. (Box-folder 2:24)
    - E. C. Lewis portrait of Edgar Allan Poe, "Ultima Thule" derivative n.d., 6 items. Photographs, Print. (Box-folder 2:25)
      #RG-5/7/2.762
    - J. A. McDougall portrait of Edgar Allan Poe 1846, 2 items. Photostats. (Box-folder 2:26)
    - "The Memorial" portrait of Edgar Allan Poe n.d., 3 items. Photographs. (Box-folder 2:27)
    - Samuel S. Osgood portrait of Edgar Allan Poe n.d., 3 items. (Box-folder 2:28)
      #38-135, #6577
    - Samuel S. Osgood portrait of Edgar Allan Poe, engraving derivative by A. W. Graham n.d., 1 item. (Box-folder 2:29)
    - Rembrandt Peale portrait of Edgar Allan Poe n.d., 2 items. Photostats. (Box-folder 2:30)
    - A. C. Smith portrait of Edgar Allan Poe, derivatives n.d., 3 items. Printed. (Box-folder 2:31)
      Published in Graham's Magazine, 1845. #38-135
    - Thomas Sully portrait of Edgar Allan Poe n.d., 1 item. Photograph. (Box-folder 2:32)
    - Anonymous portrait of Edgar Allan Poe n.d., 3 items. Printed. (Box-folder 2:33)
      "An unpublished portrait from a painting on copper. Artist unknown."
    - Anonymous portrait of Edgar Allan Poe n.d., 1 item. Printed. (Box-folder 2:34)
    - Anonymous portrait of Edgar Allan Poe, "Stella" derivative n.d., 1 item. Photograph. (Box-folder 2:35)
      #RG-23/34/1.411
    - Anonymous silhouette of Edgar Allan Poe n.d., 1 item. Photostat. (Box-folder 2:36)
  - Prints, Engravings, Lithographs
    - Henry Adlard engraving of "Stella" n.d., 1 engraving. (Box-folder 2:37)
      Based on photograph of Stella by E. A. Lewis. #38-135
    - F. Soule Campbell lithograph of Edgar Allan Poe 1921, 1 item. Printed reproduction. (Box-folder 2:38)
      Autographed note on verso: "Presented to me by Mrs. Campbell at the meeting of the Edgar Allan Poe Society, Times Square Theater, N.Y. April 24, 1921. C.A.S."
    - Oscar E. Cesare sketch of Edgar Allan Poe n.d., 1 item. Photograph. (Box-folder 2:39)
      #9477
    - Nicolas-Francois Chifflart etching of Edgar Allan Poe n.d., 1 item. Magazine clipping. (Box-folder 2:40)
    - Thomas Cole engraving of Edgar Allan Poe n.d., 1 item. Magazine clipping. (Box-folder 2:41)
    - Ferdinand Horvarth etching of Edgar Allan Poe 1930, 1 item. Etching. (Box-folder 2:42)
      #10251
    - Carl S. Junge etching of Edgar Allan Poe [ca. 1915 April], 1 item. Printed. (Box-folder 2:43)
      Verso: "From Guido Bruno, Washington Square, N.Y. April 1915."
    - LeFort engraving of Edgar Allan Poe [ca. 1894], 6 items. Etching and Photographic reproductions. (Box-folder 2:44)
      #6526-k, #38-135
    - Edouard Manet lithographs of Edgar Allan Poe n.d., 2 items. Photograph and photostat. (Box-folder 2:45)
      #38-135-a
    - Edouard Manet lithograph proof of Edgar Allan Poe [ca. 1888?], 1 items. Lithograph. (Box-folder 2:46)
      Signed by Edouard Manet. With two photostats of original. #38-135
    - Rosenmayer Lithograph of Edgar Allan Poe n.d., 1 item. Photostat. (Box-folder 2:47)
      #59
    - William Edwin Rudge etching of Edgar Allan Poe 1930, 1 item. Photostat. (Box-folder 2:48)
      Two copies. #10251
    - John Sartain engraving of Edgar Allan Poe, Osgood derivative n.d., 5 items. Photographs, prints, etching. (Box-folder 2:49)
    - Bernhardt Wall engraving of Edgar Allan Poe 1919, 1 item. (Box-folder 2:49A)
      #10602, item 11
    - Thomas B. Welch and Adam B. Walter steel engraving of Edgar Allan Poe n.d., 1 item. Printed. (Box-folder 2:50)
      Published by J. C. Buttre. #10213-b
    - Engraving of Edgar Allan Poe, Whitman derivative n.d., 2 items. Engravings. (Box-folder 2:51)
    - Postcard of Edgar Allan Poe, Whitty derivative n.d., 1 item. Postcard. (Box-folder 2:52)
    - Raven Society photographs regarding Edgar Allan Poe n.d., Photographs (Box-folder 2:53)